It will take your breath away. All of it.
Dead & Buried is a horror, mystery film directed by Gary Sherman.
After a series of gory murders commited by mobs of townspeople against visiting tourists, the
corpses appear to be coming back to life and living normally as locals in the small town.
Sheriff Dan Gillis, played by James Farentino.
Janet Gillis, played by Melody Anderson.
William G. Dobbs, played by Jack Albertson.
Ron, played by Dennis Redfield.
Linda, played by Nancy Locke.
Girl on the Beach / Nurse Lisa, played by Lisa Blount.
Dead & Buried is a 1981 American horror film directed by Gary Sherman,
starring Melody Anderson, Jack Albertson, and James Farentino.
It is Albertson's final live-action film role before his
death six months after the film's release.
The film focuses on a small town wherein a few tourists are
murdered, but their corpses begin to reanimate.
With a screenplay written by Dan O'Bannon and Ronald Shusett, the film
was initially banned as a "video nasty" in the U.K.
in the early 1980s, but was later acquitted of obscenity charges and
removed from the Director of Public Prosecutions' list.
The film made little money at the box office, but has received praise from critics
regarding Stan Winston's special effects and Albertson's performance.
In addition to the film being subsequently novelized by Chelsea Quinn Yarbro, the
film has obtained a cult following in the years since its release.
The film explores themes of small town, sheriff, voodoo, grave, murder.
The tone is dark and mind_bending.